该死，手里拿着饮料 没有酒，没有香烟
Bloody hell Soft drink in hand no alcohol, no cigarettes
这感觉就像我在一个偏僻的地方做冥想
It feels like I'm doing dynamic meditation in a hermitage
保重，你看起来很帅
Stay blessed You're looking handsome
谁会只用可乐开派对？
Who throws a party with just cola?
更好的是，还有街上的冰棍
Better than this, would have been ice-pops from the street
印度消费者普拉纳夫非常容易受骗
Pranav Bhai, the Indian consumer is very gullible
- 是吗?-他会选可乐而不是冰棒
- Is it? - Instead of ice-pops, he will choose cola
所有这些外国公司都在等着把可乐带到印度
All these foreign companies are waiting to bring colas to India
真的吗？
Really?
你总是谈生意
You always talk business
把生意牵扯进来
and drag business into everything
等等，你打算投资一家可乐公司吗？
Hold on Are you planning to invest in a Cola company?
现在忘了商业和投资吧
Forget business and investment now
- 好好享受派对，干杯-好的
- Enjoy the party Drink up - Okay
但是我必须要说
But can I say something?
你根本不会开派对
You don't know how to throw a party
好吧，我不知道
[Harshad] 'Fine, I don't'
- 你要和 Ketan 一起去伦敦，对吗?-是的
- You're going to London with Ketan, right? - Yes
在那里你可以尽情狂欢，对吧？
There you can party how you want Right?
你喜欢喝什么啤酒？
What's that beer you like?
请不要提醒我
Please don't remind me
- 百威-对，就是那个
- Budweiser - Yes, that one
跟我想的一样
Just what I thought
罢工期间我将去伦敦
I'll go to London during the strike
我马上就去
I'll make a quick trip
但我只是想知道
But I just got to know
SEBI 和经纪人即将达成和解
that SEBI and the brokers are close to a settlement
交易所很快就会开放
And the market is going to open again
很好，我们的 SBI 问题也解决了
Good Our SBI problem is solved too
现在普拉纳夫大哥，只有一个目标
Now Pranav Bhai, there's only one target
像公牛一样进入市场，用推土机碾压每个人
To enter the market like a bull and run a bulldozer over everyone
清理所有人
Clean up everyone
这个关于哈沙德和 SBI 的事情
This talk about Harshad and SBI
- 确认了吗?-百分之百
-[Manu] 'Is it confirmed?' - One hundred percent
梅塔这次会完蛋的
Mehta will be finished this time
他有大麻烦了
He's in deep shit
过去几天以来，雷克萨斯一直停在 SBI
Since the past few days, the Lexus is always at SBI
他们说他经常跑来跑去
They say that he's been running to and fro so often
他可能会晕倒
he might get dizzy and collapse
他已经归还了一大笔钱，但还剩下一些
He has returned a big chunk, but there is some left
市场关闭了，他也没有在外面做过任何交易
The market is closed and he hasn't made any transactions outside
那么，你们想做什么？
So, what do you guys want to do?
没有人知道他是从哪里得到这笔钱来偿还 SBI 的债务
Nobody knows where is he getting the money to repay SBI
他还没有清算任何股票
He hasn't liquidated any of his stocks
一旦 SBI 的新闻正式公开
Once the SBI news officially becomes public
我们就有机会压低哈沙德的股价
we will have a chance to push down Harshad's stocks
人们会失去对他的信任
People will lose trust in him
我认为这是最好的机会
I think this is the best opportunity
机会个屁
Opportunity, my foot
说话像个傻瓜！
Spoken like a fool!
你们都没有哈沙德的头脑
None of you have Harshad's brains
在新闻发布之前
Before the news breaks out
他会平仓赚钱
he'll square off his position and make profits
现在正在罢工
There is a strike
如果市场不开盘，他将如何平仓？
How will he square off his position if the market doesn't open?
去他妈的，你们能不能清醒一下
F****rs, at least keep yourselves updated
难道你不知道
Don't you know
经纪人和证券交易所已经达成和解
the brokers and SEBI have reached a settlement
市场明天开盘
The market will open tomorrow
和解可以拖延，不是吗？
The settlement can be dragged on, can't it?
这是马努大哥的市场
It's Manu Bhai's market
你只需要给出一个信号
You just have to give a signal
还需要罢工多少天？
For how many days will it need to remain closed?
直到消息传出去
Until the news comes out
市场只有在全面恐慌时才能开盘
The market should only open once there is panic all around
这样他在市场上就完蛋了
He'll be finished in the market
而且他也不能归还SBI剩下的债务
and also won't be able to return the money he has taken to repay SBI
你在股票市场上给他一刀
[AK] 'You kill him in the share market'
我们将在货币市场上再给他一刀
We will stab him in the money market
我来处理孟买的事
I'll handle Bombay
但是其他的证券交易所呢？
But what about the other stock exchanges?
加尔各答交给我吧
Leave Calcutta to me
无论如何，焦点都在孟买
And anyway, everyone will follow BSE
但是这个 SBI 的消息一定要尽快出来
But this SBI news should come out soon
我们不能让罢工持续太久
We can't hold the strike for too long
先生，我是来自SBI（印度国家银行）的沙拉德·贝拉里
Sir, I'm Sharad Bellary from SBI
先生，带我去见任何人 我时间不多了，先生
Sir, take me to anyone I don't have much time, Sir
SBI 有个大问题，先生
There is a huge problem at SBI, sir
请把他带到苏切塔女士的办公室
Please take him to Sucheta ma'am
你甚至无法想象这个骗局有多大
You can't even begin to imagine how big the fraud is
欺诈？
Fraud?
SBI 的账目上少了50亿卢比
Five hundred crores are missing from the books of SBI
你知道谁是这个骗局的幕后黑手吗？
Do you know who is behind this fraud?
哈尔沙德 · 梅塔
H-Harshad Mehta
- 我去给你倒杯茶-我不想喝茶夫人
- I'll get you a cup of tea - I don't want tea, ma'am
- 不，请等一下-夫人，我不想喝茶
- No, please Just a minute - Ma'am, I don't want tea
我马上回来，求你了！
I'll be right back Please!
- 你好-你好，我是苏切塔
- Hello - Hello Yeah, Sucheta here
听着，我们得赶紧叙叙旧
Listen, we need to catch up very urgently
我们终于掌握了一些真正的证据
We have finally got some real evidence
消息来源就在我面前
The source is right in front of me
他说哈尔沙德可能和 SBI 有麻烦了
and he says Harshad might be in some serious trouble with SBI
- 和 SBI?-是的
- With SBI? - Yes
他就在这里 我是说，他在我办公室里
He's right here I mean, he is in the cabin
[ Sucheta ]“我只是需要你给我解释一些技术细节，我们能见个面吗? ”
[Sucheta] 'I just need you to explain a few technicalities to me Can we meet?'
当然可以
Yeah, sure
好的，谢谢，再见
Okay, thank you Thank you I'll see you, bye
坐在这里的那位先生去了哪里？
Where is the gentleman who was sitting here?
我给他带了茶，我不知道他去哪了
I brought tea for him I don't know where he's gone
哦，不！
Oh, no!
出租车！
Taxi!
喂，是的，请帮我接德巴希？
Hello Yes Can you connect me to Debashis, please?
你确定这个沙拉德·贝拉里在 SBI 总部工作吗？
Are you sure this Sharat Bellary works at SBI head office?
他会不会提供了假消息给你？
and he hasn't fed you some fake news?
沙拉德·贝拉里
Sharad "D" Sharad Bellary
我不知道，但是，听起来很随便
I don't know but It sounds very convenient to me
事实上我认为是照本宣科，听着
Scripted, in fact Look
这个人不是来自财政部或账户管理部
Not from Treasury or Accounts
而是一个公关部门的人，来到了印度时报大楼
But a person from a PR department lands up in TOI building
并且只把消息告诉了你一个人
and gives this story to no one but you
然后消失得无影无踪
and then disappears without a word
Agantuk
意思是“陌生人”
It means "The Stranger"
这可能是萨蒂亚吉特 · 雷的最后一部电影
It might be Satyajit Ray's last film
你知道他的情况，对吧？
You know his condition, right?
我正在写一篇关于他的文章
I was writing an article on it for a change
被 SBI 的陌生人困住了! 真奇怪！
and got trapped by SBI's Agantuk! How strange!
我同意这不是巧合
Agreed This isn't a coincidence
他被安排到我这里来了，但是不管是谁送他来的
He's been sent to me But whoever has sent him
这个人一定知道只有我能跟进哈沙德的故事
knows, that only I can follow up on Harshad's story
这个故事是可以栽赃的，苏切塔
And this story could be planted, Sucheta
因为这个“陌生人”消失的方式
Because the way this 'Sharad', disappeared
我不认为他有任何证据
I don't think he had any evidence
这样，你去 SBI 交叉核对？
Do one thing, go to SBI and cross-check?
交叉核对? 那你呢？
Cross-check? And what about you?
我现在不能去，我得和我的线人谈谈
I can't go right now I have to talk to my source
我需要他解释一些贝拉里告诉我的事情
I need him to explain a few things that Bellary was telling me
好吧
Okay
我们先去见见线人，然后再去 SBI
Let's meet Karamchand first, and then go to SBI
你得一个人去，我们没时间了
Debashis, you'll have to go alone We are don't have time
- 快去SBI-好的我去
- Please go to SBI - Okay, I'll go
让我先喝杯茶
Let me have tea first
去 SBI 喝茶，他们的茶真的很好喝
Have tea at SBI Their tea is really good
如果你现在走，还可能会遇到哈萨德
And if you go now, you might run into Harshad
跟他一起喝茶吧
Have a couple of sips with him too Please
求你了
Please
- 拜托，德巴希斯，快去吧-我这就去
- Please, Debashis, go - I'm going I'm going!
- 我能喝这个吗?-请便
- Can I have this? - Please
你好
Hello
你找哪位？
Whom would you like to meet?
沙拉德·贝拉里
Sharat Bella Sharad Bellary
- 姓名?-女士我刚告诉你了，我找沙拉德·贝拉里
- Name? - Ma'am, I just told you Sharad Bellary
- 你叫什么，先生?-哦，对不起
- Your name, sir? - Oh, sorry
德巴希斯
Debashis
我是他表弟，从加尔各答来的
I'm his cousin from Calcutta
我住在那里，今晚坐火车回去，所以我想见见沙拉德大哥
I live there I'm taking a train back tonight so I thought Sharad Bhai
女士 有点急事
Ma'am It's a bit urgent, please
-他在哪个部门?-公关部
- Which department did you say? - PR
等一下
[Receptionist] 'One second'
“你好，沙拉德·贝拉里的表弟来看他了”
'Hello Sharad Bellary's cousin is here to see him'
德巴希斯
'Debashis'
好的，先生，他不在办公室
Okay Sir, he's not in office
他出去了
He left a while ago
他还没回来吗？
- He hasn't come back yet?
不，他告诉我他要出去，但是
No, he had told me that he's going out but
他现在应该已经回来了
he should have been back by now
好吧
No problem
我去他的办公室里等
I'll do one thing, I'll wait in his cabin
“先生，他没有办公室”
[Receptionist] 'Sir, he doesn't have a cabin'
- 好吧!-那……
- Okay! - 'So'
那我去他的座位等
So I'll wait at his desk
先生，你哪儿也不能去，你得在这儿等着
'Sir, you can't go anywhere, You'll have to wait here'
- 好的-好的
- Okay - 'Yes'
那笔钱是怎么进入他的帐户的？
How did that money go into his account?
印度国家银行会以旁遮普国家银行的名义签发支票，对吗？
SBI would have issued the cheques in PNB's name, right?
哈沙德只是个经纪人
Harshad is just a broker
因此印度国家银行必须直接以哈尔沙德的名义签发支票
Because SBI must have issued the cheques directly in Harshad's name
这不是违法的吗? 这不是错的吗？
Isn't that illegal? Is it not wrong?
好吧！
Well!
这是公认的市场行为
It's an accepted market practice
[ DT ]“你看，当系统效率低下时  ”
[DT] 'You see, when the system is inefficient'
人们就从内部找到漏洞把它扭曲一点点
people from within, tweak it They twist and bend it a little
这样业务才能顺利进行
'So that business can carry on smoothly'
做生意的便利性
'Ease of doing business'
这种交易是建立在信任的基础上的
Such transactions work on trust
而在商业领域，信任比所有的法律规定都重要
And in business, trust is bigger than all legalities
问题出现在
The problem arises when
像哈尔沙德 · 梅塔这样的人滥用这个平行系统并将其变成犯罪
people like Harshad Mehta misuse this parallel system and turn it into a crime
他破坏了体制的信任
'You know, they They break the trust of the system'
打破了平衡
'They They ruin the equilibrium'
不管怎样，这都是错误的，不是吗？
Either way, this is wrong, right?
银行只能与其他银行进行交易
Banks can only transact with other banks
他们怎么能以经纪人的名义直接签发支票呢？
How can they issue cheques directly in the name of a broker?
因为，有时候，为了节省时间，银行会把钱转到经纪人的账户上
Because, sometimes, to save time, banks transfer money into the broker's account
然后就是经纪人的事情了，要给银行带来最好的交易
and then it's the broker's headache, how he gets them the best deals
所以
So
所以只要钱在经纪人的账户里
So, as long as the money is in the broker's account
他可以把钱投资到任何他想投资的地方？
he can invest it wherever he wants?
没错，每个人都这么做
Correct, everyone does this
每个人？
Everyone?
别那样看着我，我也一样
Don't look at me like that Even I do it
但我要确保自己不会辜负体系的信任
But I make sure I don't break the trust of the system
[ DT ]“我不会破坏它的平衡”
[DT] 'I don't disturb its balance'
苏切塔，我想
Sucheta, I think
你走错方向了，问题不在于
you're taking the wrong direction here The problem here is not
SBI 把钱转到了哈尔沙德的账户
that SBI transferred money into Harshad's account Okay?
事实上，他们之间过去一定有很多这样的交易
In fact, there must have been many such transactions between them in the past
至少五百到一千亿卢比
At least five to ten thousand crores
这就是为什么，这一次，他们在他的帐户存入了50亿卢比
That's why, this time also, they deposited 500 crores in his account
假设他拿到了证券，他会把钱还回来
assuming he has the securities and he will return the money
但我不认为他有这些证券
But I don't think he has those securities
[ DT ]“而且我认为旁遮普国家银行对此一无所知”
[DT] 'And I don't think PNB even knows anything about this'
这太疯狂了
That is crazy
是的
Yes
我想 SBI 已经听到风声了，所以他们要求他把钱还回去
I think SBI has caught wind of it That's why they're asking him to return the money
[ DT ]“你听说过假冒的BR吧? ”
[DT] 'You had heard about fake BRs?'
而这是第一次，BR根本不存在
This is the first time that, the BRs don't exist at all
这就是一个骗局！
Now that is a scam!
哪个部门？
Which department?
我是贝拉里先生的表弟
I'm Bellary ji's cousin
贝拉里? 哪个贝拉里？
Bellary? Who Bellary?
沙拉德 · 贝拉里
Sharad Bellary
沙拉德 · 贝拉里？
Sharad Bellary?
他在哪个部门工作？
Which department does he work in?
- 公关部门-好的
- PR - Okay
先生，你是哪个部门的？
Sir, which department are you in?
我从事贷款业务
I work in loans
老实说
To be honest
我是来见哈沙德的
I'm here to meet Harshad Bhai
我听说他也在这里？
I heard that he's here too?
我是他的超级粉丝
I'm a big fan
-哈尔沙德·梅塔?-是的
- Harshad Mehta? - Yes
他开进口的雷克萨斯来了吗？
Has he come in his imported Lexus?
我不知道
I don't know
对不起，我得走了，谢谢
Sorry, I have to leave Thank you
谢谢
Oh Thank you
你是哪个部门的？
Which department?
- HR-好的
- HR - Okay
我以前没见过你
I haven't seen you before
真巧，我也没见过你
What a coincidence I haven't seen you either
哦，不，我上个月才入职的
Oh no, no I just joined last month
哦，好吧，那不奇怪，谢谢
Oh, okay No wonder Thanks
我去打几个电话
I'll make a few phone calls
如果获取到更多的信息，我会告诉你的
I'll let you know if I get some more information
我会和我在市场上的熟人谈谈
And I'll talk to my contacts in the market
另外我还要和哈沙德谈谈
Plus, I need to talk to Harshad as well
你要直接跟他谈吗？
You'll talk to him directly?
这是他的故事，我需要知道他的立场
The story is on him, I need to know his side as well
这是一篇调查报道
And this is an investigative piece
如果不知道他是怎么说的，听起来就像是流言蜚语
Without knowing his side of the story, it'll seem like gossip
我不想让人觉得我是那种记者，所以
I don't want to seem like that kind of a journalist So
- 谢谢-祝你好运
- Thanks - Good luck
改变世界
Change the world
我一定会努力的
I will surely try
- 你好-你好，梅塔先生？
- Hello - Hello, Mr Mehta?
- 请讲-我是苏切塔 · 达拉尔
- Speaking - This is Sucheta Dalal
现在方便讲话吗？
Is this a good time to talk?
这取决于这个电话是建设性的还是破坏性的？
Depends Is this call constructive or destructive?
梅塔先生我只是想确认一下
Mr Mehta, I just wanted to check
我们刚刚得知你们未能如期交付
We've just been informed that you've failed to deliver securities
价值50亿卢比的证券给印度国家银行
'worth 500 crores to the State Bank of India'
现在他们要求退款，你对此有什么回应吗
'And now they're demanding their money back Would you care to comment?'
没有
No
为什么？
Why not?
因为这毫无根据，毫无意义
Because it's baseless, it's nonsense
像你这样的记者不适合煽动这种谣言
And it doesn't suit a journalist like you to fan such rumours
你确定吗梅塔先生? 因为我有线人
Are you sure, Mr Mehta? Because I have sources
也许能证实这一点
who might be able to confirm this
“听着，你想要我的回应，我给你了”
[Harshad] 'Look, you wanted my reaction and you got it'
现在，你想让我说一些你可以发表的东西
Now, you want me to say something that you can print
SBI 知道真相，我也知道
SBI knows the truth, and so do I
这么说你否认了？
So you're denying it?
苏切塔女士，在金融世界里没有空间听这种无聊的闲言碎语
Sucheta ji, there's no room for such filmy gossip in the financial world
- 你的消息来源是谁?-谢谢，梅塔先生
- Anyway, who is your source? - Thank you, Mr Mehta
哈沙德，如果这篇文章发表了，就会打开潘多拉的盒子
Harshad, if this gets published it'll open a pandora's box
什么都不会发表
Nothing will get published
- 没有消息-似乎有
- There is no news - There seems to be
她听起来很坚决
She sounded determined
所以我才叫你别偷听我的电话
That's why I ask you not to eavesdrop on my calls
如果她有证据，她会直接发表的，不会打电话给我
If she had proof, she would have published it She wouldn't have called me
他们知道我在这个行业里是个大人物
They know that I'm the real deal in this business
如果他们在没有证据的情况下发表任何东西，他们就有麻烦了
If they publish anything without proof, they'll be in trouble
那你还在等什么？
So what are you waiting for?
让他们知道你不是开玩笑的
Show them that you're the real deal
哈尔沙德 · 梅塔？
Harshad Mehta?
接过来
Put him through
50亿，你在开玩笑吗？
500 crores Are you joking?
听着，可能会更多
Listen It can be even more
是的，有可能我自己也见过他几次
Yes, it's possible I've seen him a few times myself
三天前，有一大群人只是为了看看他的车
Three days back, there was a crowd just to look at his car
- 哪辆车-雷克萨斯
- Which car is it - Lexus
是的，雷克萨斯
Yes, Lexus
是谁告诉你这50亿的？
But who told you about this 500 crore?
兄弟，每个人都知道，但他们保持沉默
Brother, everyone knows, but they are keeping mum
因为如果事情曝光，有些高级官员会受到惩罚
Because if it becomes public, even the senior officials will get f****d
- 你是认真的吗?-嗯
-Are you serious? -Hmmm
西塔拉曼先生，来这边
Sitaraman ji, please come
- 那是谁?-他什么都知道
- Who's that? - He will know everything
我们正在谈论你的部门
We were just talking about your department
- 是吗? 你们在说什么?-是的
- Is it? What were you talking about? - Yes
还是老样子，哈尔沙德 · 梅塔的案子
The same Harshad Mehta case
- 这位先生说金额有50亿-胡说！
- This gentleman here says, 500 crores have - Nonsense!
绝对的谣言
Absolute rubbish
除了在餐厅里闲聊，你就没别的事可做了吗？
Don't you have anything better to do, than gossip in the canteen?
Mehta 先生和 SBI 做了很多生意
Mr Mehta and SBI do a lot of business
因此，有时会计会出错，但现在一切都解决了
So sometimes the accounting goes wrong, but it's all settled now
真的吗? 50亿他都还清了？
All of it? All 500 crores?
不，还有一点未结清，只有六七千万卢比
No, a little is pending Only six or seven crores
这两天就会结清了
That will be done day after tomorrow
你们最好别再散布谣言了
You guys better stop spreading these rumours
如果卡马尼先生知道这件事，他会让你们俩停职
If Mr Khemani hears about this he will suspend you both
先生，这是他说的，跟我们没关系
Sir, he was saying What do we care? It's not even our department
对
Right
你来自哪个部门？
Which department are you from?
公关部
PR
你刚不是说人力资源部？
HR?
是的 我加入才几天
Yes It's only been a few days since I joined
公关还是人力资源？
PR or HR?
人力资源
HR
- 喝点茶吧-不了，我有急事
- Have some tea at least - No, I have something urgent to do
好吧，我也该走了，我还有很多工作要做
Okay, I should leave too I have a lot of work to do
- 谢谢-最近有新员工入职你们部门吗？
- Thank you - Has anyone joined your department recently?
没有，怎么了？
No, why?
那边那个人，不是你们部门的吗？
That man over there Isn't he from your department?
谁？
Who?
- 好的
- Okay -[typewriter clicking]
- 两年前-好的明白了
Two years back Okay, got it
好了，我一会儿再打给你
Okay No, listen I'll have to call you back
怎样? 我们还是去会议室谈吧
So? Actually, you know what, let's talk in the conference room
- 为什么?-来吧 来吧
- But why? - Come Just come
- 怎么了?-只是 人太多了
- What happened? - Just too many people
“不行”
[Debashis] 'No'
我想他在见过你之后就消失了
I think he's disappeared after meeting you
但是苏切塔，贝拉里似乎说的是实话
But Sucheta, Bellary seems to be telling the truth
哈尔沙德经常去SBI
Harshad has been regularly visiting SBI
似乎有什么隐情
meetings are happening Something seems to be brewing
-拿到任何证据了吗?-没有
- So what do we have now? - Nothing much
哈尔沙德会签出最后一张支票，数额很小
Harshad is giving the last cheque day after tomorrow It's a small amount
他的债务也会被清偿，到时候就没有报道了
And his dues will be cleared up There's no news
如果罪犯清理了犯罪现场
If a criminal cleans up the crime scene
这是否意味着犯罪行为从未发生过？
does that mean the crime never happened?
他滥用体系漏洞，把这个体系搞得一团糟
He has messed with the system and misused it
- 所以他才要还钱-告诉我
That's why he is repaying the money Tell me one thing, Debashis
这些资金来自哪里？
Where are the funds coming from?
每一分钱都属于印度人民
Every single penny belongs to the people of India
他怎么能像用他爸的钱一样随便呢？
How can he use it like his father's money?
他想用就用，赚了钱就还上！
Used it whenever he wanted, earned profit on it and returned it!
如果他亏损了怎么办? 如果他还不回去怎么办？
What if he had made a loss? What if he couldn't have returned it?
苏切塔，一旦剩下的钱还清，我们就没有报道了
Sucheta, once the rest of the money is returned, we don't have a story
就这么简单
As simple as that
你认为 SBI 的人会开口吗？
Do you think the people at SBI will speak about this?
我要确保今晚这个故事能够公之于众
This is why I'm going to make sure the story comes out tonight
在他把剩下的钱还回来之前
before he returns the rest of the money
你好！
Hello!
苏切塔，我们是在做关于哈尔沙德·梅塔的报道吗？
Sucheta, are we doing a story on Harshad Mehta?
“你怎么知道的? ”
[Sucheta] 'How did you know?'
他打来了电话，否认了一切
He called, he denied everything
你有他的证词吗，他到底否认了什么？
Do you have his statement, what has he denied exactly?
你有什么证据支持你的说法吗？
Do you have anything to support your story?
我有消息来源
I have my sources
你的线人能公开发言吗？
Will they speak on record?
不能，但我通过多种渠道交叉核对了所有信息
No But I've cross-checked all the facts through multiple channels
苏切塔，你要知道，这是印度时报
Sucheta, you need to understand this is the Times of India
没有实际的书面证据，不能发表任何东西
Without actual paper evidence, you can't print anything
我不能让你继续
I can't give you the go-ahead
我对我的资料来源有信心，在过去，我们发表过
I have faith in my sources and in the past, people have published
没有任何书面证据的很多文章
many articles without any paper evidence
我希望你能理解，如果消息不是真的
I hope you understand that he can even sue us
他甚至可以起诉我们
if the news is not true
拉杰迪普，如果你不让我发表
Rajdeep, if you won't let me publish this
那我就去找迪里普了
then I'm going to have to go to Dileep
当然，去吧，我相信他也会这么说的
Sure, go for it I'm sure he'll say the same thing
我们不会公开宣称‘我们是最勇敢的’
We don't claim publicly that 'we are the most courageous'
但是如果这个国家有一家新闻出版社采取强硬立场
But if there is a news publication in this country that takes a tough stance
那我们就是救世主
then we are the one
我们不区分强者和弱者
We don't differentiate between the powerful and the weak
你们的报纸最近是不是太亲政府了？
Hasn't your newspaper been too pro-government lately?
事实上，他们一直是亲政府的
In fact, they were always pro-government
迪里普，告诉我
Dileep, tell me something
英国人还在支付你的薪水吗？
Are the British still paying your salary?
我们和别人的区别是
The difference between others and us is
我们不再无意义地批评政府
that we don't keep on criticising the government pointlessly
我们不仅仅是为了指出系统中的缺陷
We are not here to just point out the faults in the system
拜托 迪里普先生
Oh Come on Mr Dileep
把这些政治上正确的答案留给我们这些政客吧
Leave these politically correct answers to us politicians
不是吗？
Am I right?
对不起，帕德冈卡先生
Sorry, Mr Padgaonkar
但你一定听说过那句话
But you must have heard the saying
《泰晤士报》就像风一样？
"The Times" flows the way the wind blows Huh?
实际上，《时代》是按照《时代》的方式发展的
Actually, "The Time" flows the way "The Times" goes
先生，您有一个从孟买打来的重要电话
Mr Padgaonkar, you have an important call from Bombay
对不起，先生们，我有个电话要接
Excuse me, gentlemen I have a call to take
- 你好-你好
- Hello - Hello
先生，我是苏切塔
Sir, Sucheta here
先生，很抱歉打扰你，但这是非常紧急的事情
Sir, sorry to bother you but this is very urgent
苏切塔 · 达拉尔？
Sucheta Dalal?
是的，先生，从孟买打来的
[Sucheta] 'Yes, sir, from Bombay'
你怎么知道我在这儿？
How did you know I'm here?
先生，说来话长现在，我想跟您讨论一些重要的事情
Sir, it's a long story Right now, I want to discuss something important
继续，我在听
[Dileep] 'Go ahead, I'm listening'
先生，我有个独家新闻
Sir, I have a scoop
哈尔沙德·梅塔诈骗了 SBI 五十亿卢比
Harshad Mehta has defrauded SBI of 500 crores
[ Sucheta ]“没有人对此有丝毫的暗示”
[Sucheta] 'and no one has the slightest hint about it'
我有一个主要消息来源，来自印度国家银行的公关部门
I have a primary source from the SBI, PR department
他今天上午来到办公室，把所有的细节都告诉了我
He came into office this morning and gave me all the details
先生，我真的很想继续这个故事
Sir, I really want to go ahead with this story
那又怎样? 有什么问题吗
[Dileep] 'So? What's the problem?'
先生，拉杰迪普不同意
Sir, Rajdeep is not agreeing
他说因为我没有任何书面证据
He says that because I don't have any paper evidence
不能让我继续报道这件事
he cannot allow me to go forward with the story
你没有证据？
You have no evidence?
“你的线人……”
[Dileep] 'Your source'
没有，但是我已经做了全面的背景调查，我很确定
No, sir But I've done a complete background check I'm sure of this
“我明白，苏切塔”
[Dileep] 'I understand, Sucheta'
但还是试着找到一些证据
But try and find some evidence of any kind
没有证据，我们不能发表这么大的报道
Without any evidence, we can't publish a story this big
“你应该明白这一点”
[Dileep] 'You should understand that'
先生，但是这个故事明天就会过时
Sir, but this story will be dead by tomorrow
哈尔沙德正在调整资金
Harshad is retuning the funds
明天，他就会把最后一张支票存进去
and by the day after, he'll have deposited the last cheque as well
那么就没有报道了
So, there's no story then
他把钱拿走了，又把钱还回去了
He took the money, and has returned it back
这不是一笔他可以随时归还的贷款
This isn't a loan that he can return whenever he wants
他滥用政府的钱来操纵证券交易所的股价
He's misusing money from the government to rig shares in the stock exchange
你觉得这是他第一次这么做吗？
And do you think this is his first time he's done it?
或者他只是和 SBI 一起做了这件事，以后不会再犯了？
Or that he has only done it with SBI and won't repeat it ever!?
先生哈尔沙德·梅塔人脉很广
Sir, Harshad Mehta is very well connected
银行方面拿他没办法，但是我们可以
SBI won't do anything but we can
我们记者什么时候开始不追查
I mean, when did we journalists stop going after criminals
那些没人向当局举报的罪犯了
just because nobody has reported them to the authorities
我给你出个主意
I'll give you a solution
打电话给 SBI，直接询问他们是否与哈尔沙德·梅塔
Call up SBI and ask them directly if such a transaction took place
进行了这样的交易
between them and Mr Mehta
[迪里普]“应该由某位高级官员确认”
[Dileep] 'Confirmation should be from some high official'
如果他们确认了，我们就继续
'If they confirm it, we go ahead'
否则，我们就不能发表
Otherwise, we cannot do it
好的，先生，知道了，谢谢
Okay, sir Got it Thank you
他不同意，对吧？
He didn't agree, right?
他希望 SBI 的高级管理层予以确认
He wants confirmation from SBI's senior management
你为什么不直接和印度国家银行的主席谈呢？
Why don't you talk to the SBI chairman directly?
萨切塔，在今天的版面进入印刷之前，你只有一个小时
Sucheta, you only have one hour before today's edition goes into printing
否则你的故事就完了
otherwise, your story will be dead
好吗? 碰碰运气，祝你好运
Alright? Take a chance Best of luck
先生，有你的电话
Sir, there's a call for you
你好
Hello
你好，晚上好，先生
Hello Good evening, sir
这是印度时报的苏切塔 · 达拉尔
This is Sucheta Dalal from Times of India
你好，达拉尔女士，我能为你做些什么？
Yes, Ms Dalal, what can I do for you?
先生，我直说了，哈尔沙德 · 梅塔是否诈骗了 SBI
Sir, let me be direct Is it true that Harshad Mehta defrauded SBI
-  50亿卢比?-什么？
- of 500 crores? - What?
不，我不这么认为
No, I do not think this is true at all
你从哪里得到的信息？
Where do you get your information from?
先生，我有线人
Sir, I have a source
你被消息来源误导了，达拉尔女士
Your source must be misinformed, Ms Dalal
我们之间有非常大量的交易
You see, we have very heavy transactions
有时会出现延迟收款的情况
and sometimes reconciliation is difficult Sometimes delayed
但我认为你根本不应该过分夸大这件事
I do not think you should blow this out of proportion at all
晚安
I wish you a very good evening
是的，所以他们不会刊登我的报道
Yeah, so we have the story but they won't print it
他们是谁？
Who is they?
拉杰迪普，我们的孟买编辑不同意发表
Rajdeep, our Bombay editor won't publish it
迪里普，我们的总编辑想要 SBI 的确认
And Dileep, our head editor wants a confirmation from SBI
我是说，他没有坚持要获得书面证据，但是
I mean, he's not insisting on paper evidence but
你和SBI的人谈过了吗？
So did you speak to anybody?
是的，我直接和主席通了电话，但他否认了
Yes I spoke to Goiporia directly But he denied it
我是说他不会承认任何事的，对吧？
I mean, he's not going to admit anything, right?
如果说哈尔沙德犯了诈骗罪，SBI 也不是圣人
If Harshad has committed a fraud, SBI is no saint either
[ Sucheta ]“他们也很脆弱”
[Sucheta] 'They are also vulnerable'
是的，也可能有罪，但现在怎么办？
Yeah And possibly guilty also But what now?
我不知道，你为什么问我?你能不能做点什么
I don't know Why are you asking me? Do something
我真的快没有时间了
I really don't have time
- 喂? 喂?-喂
-[Sucheta] 'Hello? Hello?' - Yes
-喂-你可能也束手无策了
- Hello -[Sucheta] 'I thought you also Anyway'
我可能认识 SBI 的高级管理人员
I might know someone from SBI's senior management
[ DT ]‘我问问他是否愿意帮助我们’
[DT] 'Let me see if he can help us'
请马上和他谈谈
Please, talk to him right away
好吧，如果他同意，我会让他打电话给你
Okay If he agrees then I'll ask him to call you
太好了 谢谢
That's great Thanks
马扬克，等等，你要去哪里？
Mayank, wait Where are you going?
我要去吃晚饭
I'm going to have dinner
把你的烟给我
Give me your pack
-这个行吗?-嗯
-I have this Will it do? -Hmm
- 你来吃晚饭吗?-不
- You're coming for dinner? - No
- 好吧-你去
- Okay, fine - You go
你会自己买一包吗？
and you'll buy your own pack?
- 好的-好的谢谢
- Okay - Okay, thanks
- 对不起，先生-不，请继续
- Oh! Sorry, sir - No, please go on
我知道，在这团烟雾的背后，一定有一个非常火爆的故事
I know, behind this cloud of smoke, there must be a smoking hot story
别停，我不想打扰你的思绪
Don't stop I don't want to disturb your chain of thought
我只是想伸伸腿
I was just going to stretch my legs
不，先生，没事的
No, sir I'm fine, thank you
这年头抽烟很正常，人人都抽烟
It's quite common these days, Everyone's smoking
顺便问一下，为什么你们普通人不抽烟？
By the way, why doesn't your Common Man smoke?
- 我有哮喘-哦，这样
- Oh! He has asthma - Oh, yes
我一直想问你一个问题，先生
I've always wanted to ask you a question, sir
为什么你说的"普通人"总是一个男人？
Why is your "Common Man" always a man?
为什么不是一个“普通女人” ？
Why not a "Common Woman"?
你看，一个女人不可能是普通的
You see, a woman cannot be common
女人总是特别的
Women are always special
- 当然-是吗？
- Sure - Right?
- 我想我应该……-是的，请吧
- I think I should - Yes Please
喂？
Hello
喂，苏切塔，我要走了
Hello, Sucheta I'm leaving now
- 要我送你回家吗?-不用了
- Should I drop you home? - No, I'm fine
贝拉里先生的故事怎么样了？
Well, what's the scene with Mr Bellary's story?
我只是需要一点时间
I just need a little more time
“还有多少时间? ”
[Debashis] 'How much more time?'
明天的报纸现在随时都可能出版
Tomorrow's edition will go to print any moment now
可能赶不上了
I doubt if they will print the story
德巴希斯，我没有心思和你争论
Debashis, I don't have the energy to argue
我在等一个很重要的电话，再见
I'm waiting for an important phone call Bye
哦，不
Oh no Everything is a mess
- 德巴希斯，我要告诉你多少次-达拉尔女士
- Debashis, how many time do I've to tell -[Man 1] 'Ms Dalal?'
你好，对不起，你是谁？
Hello I'm sorry Who is this?
“我在 SBI 工作，有人告诉我，你想和我谈谈”
[Man1] 'I work for SBI I was told you wanted to speak to me'
是的，先生，我在写一篇报道
Yes! Yes, sir I'm writing a story
- 我只是想-我知道细节
- and I just wanted -[Man1] 'I am aware of the details'
好的
Okay, good
先生，我只需要你的确认
Sir, I just needed a confirmation from you
如果我发表了这篇文章，结果是虚惊一场
if I publish this story, and it turns out to be a false alarm
那我就有大麻烦了，甚至可能会丢掉工作
then I'll be in very serious trouble I could even lose my job
“如果我的名字以任何方式突然出现，我也会丢掉工作”
[Man1] 'Even I'll lose my job if my name pops up in any way'
先生，我不需要任何名字，我甚至不想知道细节
Sir, I don't need any names, I don't even want the details
我知道你不能说太多
I know you can't say much
我只想确认我的方向是对的，先生
I just need to know if I can go ahead, sir
继续调查
Go ahead
谢谢
Thank you Thank you
太好了
Yes
苏切塔，我读了你的文章
Sucheta, I read your piece
诈骗这个词出现了很多次
You've used this word "scam" so many times
我是说我们只用金融丑闻之类的词
I mean, we use words like financial frauds or scandal, etcetera
意思都是一样的，你知道吧？
for the same thing You know it, right?
是时候在印度金融界引入这个强有力的词汇了
It's time to introduce this strong word in the Indian financial world
让读者知道，西方媒体已经采用了
To let the readers know about it I mean, the western media has already adopted it
其他国家已经发生了太多的骗局
There are so many scams happening left, right and center
记住我的话，在接下来的三四年里
Mark my words, in the next three to four years
这个词将成为常用语
this word will be common parlance
你和迪莉普谈过了吗？
Did you speak to Dileep?
我让马扬克在联系
Well, I've asked Mayank to try
打通电话我就和他谈
I'll talk to him as soon as we get through
-苏切塔-我知道
- Sucheta - I know
你还好吗？
Are you fine?
- 是的-好吧，看看你能不能搞定
- Yes - Alright See if you can work it out
先生，又有你的电话，很紧急
Sir, call for you again Sir, it's urgent
我给你带来了无绳电话
I've got the cordless for you
-喂 -先生，我已经得到确认了
- Hello - Sir, I've got a confirmation
- 官方的?-不是官方的
-[Dileep] 'Officially?' - Not officially
但这是高级管理人员给确认的，正如你所要求的
but it is from the senior management, just as you asked
这还不够，苏切塔
[Dileep] 'That's not enough, Sucheta'
先生，你还记得吗，三个月前
Sir, do you remember, three months ago
当我爆出拉詹 · 皮莱的故事时，我们也有过类似的讨论？
we had a similar discussion when I broke the Rajan Pillai story?
那时你相信了我，结果证明是真的
You believed in me then, and it turned out to be true
您甚至还在第七页上刊登了这个故事
And you even published the story on the seventh page
- 好吧，那又怎样?-所以，先生，请相信我的直觉
-[Dileep] 'Okay, so?' - So, sir, trust my gut on this
这件事必须公之于众
This needs to come out
“好吧，我会跟拉杰迪普说的，但是记住  ”
[Dileep] 'Okay, I'll talk to Rajdeep But remember'
“如果我们因此陷入麻烦，你在印度时报的时间就结束了”
'if we get into trouble because of this, your time at TOI is over'
“还想继续吗? ”
'Still want to go ahead with this?'
想！
Yes!
- 确定?-百分之五百
- 'Sure?' - Five hundred percent
好吧
[Dileep] 'Okay'
苏切塔真是太固执了
Sucheta is just being stubborn
怎么能发表反对名人的文章
How can you publish something against a celebrity
却又没有足够的证据？
without enough corroboration?
她觉得这是独家新闻
She thinks it's a scoop
独家新闻？
Scoop?
告诉她，如果她需要勺子（scoop），就去买盒冰激凌
Tell her, if she needs a scoop, go buy ice-cream
你为什么不告诉她？
Why don't you tell her that? Huh?
- 喂?-喂？
Hello? Yeah?
迪里普的电话
Dileep's on the line
苏切塔
Sucheta
头版
Front page
恭喜你
Congratulations
谁改了标题？
Who changed the headline?
文章甚至没有提到哈尔沙德 · 梅塔
Harshad Mehta is not even mentioned in this article
他到处都被称为“大公牛”
He has been referred to as "Big Bull" everywhere
我改了名字，苏切塔
I changed it, Sucheta
为什么？
Why?
这是最安全的选择，这样我们都安全了
This was the safest option This way, we all are safe
但是至少你可以问我一下啊
But you could have taken me into confidence, you could have asked me once
我和拉杰迪普和迪里普讨论了这个问题
I discussed it with Rajdeep and Dileep
这是最好的选择
And that was the best option
苏切塔! 苏切塔
Sucheta! Sucheta
发生了什么？
What happened?